准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
抢救时空大作战                                下集
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
谢谢你们大家救我
Thanks for saving me, everyone!
老爸
Dad!
你脾脏都露出来了
Your spleen is showing.
怪不得感觉有一阵凉风
I thought I felt a breeze!
让我来解决一下
Let me take care of that.
完美
Perfect!
成功了
We did it!
我照片恢复正常了
My photo's back to normal.
对啊  可是再看看这张
Yeah, but take a look at this one!
我从肥油里拔出海神黄金锅铲那会儿
The time I pulled Neptune's spatula from the grease!
可拿着锅铲的不是我
But I'm not holding it.
是你妈
Your mom is!
我妈怎么了
My mom is what?
去调查一下
Let's investigate!
请看那终极厨具
Behold the ultimate cooking utensil
黄金锅铲
the golden spatula
上面写着  众多人试图
It says here, "Many have tried
从这远古肥油中拔出这把锅铲
to pull this spatula from this ancient grease
却无功而返
and all have failed"
只有配得上海神王本人的煎炸厨师
"Only a fry cook worthy of King Neptune himself
才能使用
can wield"
黄金锅铲
"the golden spatula"
帮我跟黄金锅铲合个影
Take a picture of me and the spatula
天啊  给我干哪来了
Goodness, where am I?
老妈好
Hi, Mom
儿子好
Hello, son
海绵宝宝  别碰那脏东西
SpongeBob, don't touch that filthy thing
都不知道它都到过什么地方
We don't know where it's been
我先给它擦干净
I'll just scrub it nice and clean
拿去吧  甜心
Here you go, sweetie
谢了  星妈
Thanks, Mrs. Star
亮晶晶
So shiny
是的
Yes
终于
At last
能有人配得上皇家厨师的称号了
someone worthy of being the royal fry cook
是谁从肥油里拔出了我神奇的锅铲
Who has freed my mighty spatula from the grease?
拔出锅铲的不可能是你
There's no way you pulled the spatula out
你只是个卑贱的海绵
You are but a lowly sponge
微不足道
puny
无足轻重的弱者
an insignificant weakling
这双无力的婴儿小手
Why, these feeble little baby arms
绝无可能释放出我神圣的锅铲
could never release my divine spatula
脱离布满油污的监狱
from its greasy prison
抱歉  殿下
Sorry, your highness
不是我干的
It wasn't me
其实拔出来的是我  星妈邦妮
Actually, it was me, Bunny Star
她朋友管她叫妈
Her friends call her "Mom"
好啊
Yes
你显然更胜一筹
You are obviously superior
看看你布满肌肉的胳膊
Why, look at your muscular arms
妈妈
我天天打扫卫生  所以才这么壮
Keeping things clean keeps me fit
你有着擎天神阿特拉斯的体格
You have the physique of Atlas
跟我摆姿势
Make poses with me
你的力量如此强大  有资格担任
Clearly you possess the strength to become
海神王的御厨
the personal chef of King Neptune
我从来没给神灵下过厨
I've never cooked for a deity before
来吧  邦妮
Come, Bunny
启程前往我的皇宫
Let us depart to my palace
就在亚特兰蒂斯
in Atlantis
祝你好运  星妈
Good luck, Mrs. Star
踏板得你来蹬
You'll need to pedal
老妈拜拜
Bye, Mom
晚餐见
See you at dinner
请看我神圣的厨房
Behold my divine kitchen
神的厨房最适合
Nothing like a kitchen of the gods
来整点简单的家常菜了
to whip up a simple home-cooked meal
尽情品尝吧
Have a taste
这是什么不同寻常的味道
What is that unusual flavor?
这上等美味
Why, it's just the delicious flavor
是我的招牌靴子面汤
of my famous boot noodle soup
我没胃口了
I just lost my appetite
胡说八道
Nonsense
你这大神还在长身体呢
You're a big growing god
我不太舒服
I don't feel so good
天啊  有人拉肚子了
Oh my, someone has a case of the rumblies
in their tummy wummy
我带你上床  把你给养好
Let's get you in bed, mister, and fix you up
寡人的日程今天排得满满当当
My kingly docket is incredibly full today
但我病得不轻  恐怕无法尽职了
but I'm far too ill to complete my royal duties
我该怎么办
Whatever shall I do?
放心好了  我来帮你尽职
Don't you worry, I'll handle all your royal business
可是要怎么知道尽什么职呢
But how will I know what to do?
每当我的王国危在旦夕
When my kingdom is in peril
我强大的三叉戟都会大放异彩
my mighty trident will glow
指引你前去济世救民
and take you to where you are needed
谢了  但你到底多长时间
Thank you, but when was the last time
没好好把这三叉戟擦干净了
you gave this trident a good scrubbing?
千万别
Please
那把三叉戟可是亚特兰蒂斯远古文物
That trident is an ancient Atlantean artifact
万万不能用擦洗剂
No abrasive cleaners
天啊
Oh my
我得上工了
I have to get to work
一定要好好休息哦  甜心
Be sure you get lots of rest, sweetie
裤头村小学
看看这些小鱼儿啊
Look at the little guppies
你干嘛要带我来这里呢
Now, why did you take me here?
天啊  可不能让那个掉下来
Goodness, we can't have that
总算重新粉刷完了海之
I finally finished repainting the Chum
海之霸
霸
Bucket
小朋友们再见
Bye, kiddies
这个洞也不能破
Well, we can't have that either
我该怎么收拾干净呢
How am I gonna clean all this up?
这下简单了
That was easy
裤头村
你被禁足了  大洪水
You are grounded, Mr. Flood
回你房间去
Go to your room
又要出动了
Here I go again
感谢那个谁  都结束了
Thank someone that's over
不好
Oh no
天啊  有谁发了点小脾气
Oh dear, someone's having a little temper tantrum
你冷静一点  甜心
Now, you just settle down, sweetie
我没事
I'm okay
要是有人在乎的话
If anyone cares
赞美邦妮
Praise Bunny
万岁
Hooray
你可恶
Why you
我哪有
What'd I do?
真想不到
Who knew?
我只要稍微假装一下肚子疼
All I needed to do was fake a bellyache
就能放上千载难逢的第一个假
and I'd have my first day off in a millennia
我们要中断本节目
We interrupt this program
海胆哥与败蜗子
突发新闻
插播裤头村突发新闻
for Bikini Bottom breaking news
帕奇帕金斯正在现场报道
Perch Perkins here reporting live
裤头村新晋的大英雄
on Bikini Bottom's newest hero
星妈邦妮
Bunny Star
请问一下  先生
Excuse me, sir
如何评价我们新晋的守护天使
What do you think of our new guardian angel?
有了邦妮女王  就用不上海神王了
Who needs King Neptune when we have Queen Bunny
邦妮女王
Queen Bunny?
要是有谁敢比我红  我绝对不能忍
I won't stand for anyone being more popular than me
所以这位就是你们新晋的女王了吗
So, this is your new Queen, is it?
星妈邦妮  我要向你发起
Bunny Star, I challenge thee
终极挑战擂台赛
to the ultimate contest
当场完成艰巨任务
A herculean task
从此决出谁才是海底真神
to divine who is the true god of the ocean
一听就很乐
That sounds like a hoot
大家都听到了吧
You heard it here first, folks
真神擂台赛开打了
It's time for a god-off
海神波塞殿
欢迎来到海神波塞殿
Welcome to the Poseidome
两位神灵将在此角逐
where two powerful deities will battle it out
争夺海神的王位
for Neptune's crown
你能行的  老妈
You can do it, Mom
他们的挑战
Their challenge
究竟哪位泰坦大神
Which one of these mighty titans
能击败凶残的克拉肯呢
can defeat the savage Kraken?
我海神王  将会击败克拉肯
I, King Neptune, will defeat the Kraken
用到的武器正是我的旧三叉戟
and I'll do it using my old trident
二叉戟
bident
放出克拉肯
Release the Kraken
派大星  快带你妈走
Quick, Patrick, grab your mom
我爱你的新造型  老妈
I love your new look, Mom
那不是你妈
That's not your mom
嗨  甜心
Hi, sweetie
看来只剩我们两个了  克拉肯
Looks like it's just you and me, Kraken
尝尝我海神王的怒火  你这肮脏野兽
Taste the mighty fury of Neptune, you foul beast
你管谁叫肮脏野兽
Who you callin' foul beast?
你自己也没好看到哪里去
You're no beauty queen yourself, fella
这下想起来干嘛要雪藏这旧东西了
Now I remember why I put this old thing in storage
我都忘了
I forgot
你三叉戟还在我手上
I still have your trident
而且我还特地给它擦干净了
And I made sure to give it a good scrubbing
感受我无敌三叉戟的神力吧
Feel the might of my invincible trident
早跟她说过不能用擦洗剂的
I told her no abrasive cleaners
谁知道原来海神王这么好吃
Who knew Neptune tasted so good?
改天还要再吃他一次
I think I'll try him a second time
这就是旷工的下场
This is what I get for playing hooky from work
这味道就是鸡
Tastes like chicken
皇饭
à la King
成功了
We did it!
救回老妈了
We rescued Mom!
最好检查一下照片
We'd better check the photo.
感谢海神王  都恢复正常了
Thank Neptune, it's back to normal.
感觉不太应该感谢海神王吧
Not sure we should be thanking Neptune for anything.
派大爷还在迷离时空
GrandPat is still lost in time!
检查一下别的照片
Let's check the other photos!
我在蟹堡王上班的第一天
My first day working at the Krusty Krab!
那不是我
Well, that's not me.
是派大爷
It's GrandPat!
我都不知道派大爷会下厨
I didn't know GrandPat could cook!
来看看是怎么个事情
Come on, let's see what happened.
一定会特好看
This is gonna be good!
我准备好了
I'm ready
加油  海绵宝宝
Go, SpongeBob
到了
There it is
有史以来最棒的提供饮食的餐厅
The finest eating establishment
ever established for eating
蟹堡王
The Krusty Krab
蟹黄堡之家
"Home of the Krabby Patty"
窗户上还贴着招
With a "Help Wanted" sign in the--
招聘
恭喜你了  派大爷
Congratulations, GrandPat
你就是我们新任的煎炸厨师了
You're our new fry cook
希望你给旧日损友干活不会有问题
I hope it's not a problem working for your old frenemy
我才没给你干活呢  老螃蟹
I'm not working for you, Krabs
我是在你旁边干活
I'm working near you
你说了算  老东西
Whatever you say, old-timer
我准备好过
I was ready
此处点餐
是那个送报纸的
It's the paperboy
我早就没在给你送报纸了
I'm not your paperboy anymore
在我心中  你永远都在给我送报纸
To me you'll always be my paperboy
送报纸的
Paperboy
我在全世界最好的水下餐厅都下过厨
I've worked in the world's finest underwater kitchens
比方说从凡尔赛的喷泉
From the fountains of Versailles
再到泰姬陵的倒影池
to the reflecting pool of the Taj Mahal
这垃圾堆轻轻松松就能搞定
I can easily handle this dump
来给自己来整点东西吃好了
I think I'll make myself something to eat
我准备好过
I was ready
听起来像舱门打开的声音
That sounded like hatch doors
你闻到了吗
Do you smell it?
那味道
That smell
某种难闻的味道
A kind of smelly smell
这难闻的味道  味道又很
A smelly smell that smells
难闻
smelly
别看我
Don't look at me
我只闻到了凤尾鱼味
All I smell are anchovies
凤尾鱼
Anchovies?
什么
What?
凤尾鱼
Anchovies
派大爷
GrandPat
做蟹黄堡啊
Start cooking Krabby Patties
快
pronto
我只要求你们排好队
One single file line is all I ask
关我屁事
The heck with this
祝你好运  老螃蟹
Good luck, Krabs
我不干了
I quit
谁呲我
Who's psssssting me?
不是我
It wasn't me
看下面
Down here
跟你说  我付你一块钱
I tell ya what, I'll give you one dollar
买那个蟹黄堡
for that Krabby Patty
痞老板
Plankton?
这蟹黄堡太大了  你这小不点吃不下
This patty's too big for a little squirt like you
你这就叫胃口大  肚子小
Your eye is bigger than your stomach
我没要拿来吃  你个白痴无脊椎动物
I'm not gonna eat it, you imbecilic invertebrate
我拿它有
I need it for, uh
别的用途
something else
那样的话  就给你吧
In that case you can have it
条件是先给我付五百块
for five hundred smackers
什么
What?
好吧
All right
还是比杀手机器人便宜
It's still cheaper than a killer robot
不吃是吧
Not gonna eat it, eh?
你是打算把那蟹黄堡怎么了  矮冬瓜
Whatcha plannin' on doin'
with that Krabby Patty, short stuff?
既然你真要问
Well, if you must know
我要统治世界
I'm gonna rule the world
是吗
Oh yeah?
首先我会复制这个蟹黄堡
First, I'll replicate this patty
厨房
接着用卖蟹黄堡赚来的钱
Then with all the money I make from selling them
召集一支可怕的克隆大军
I'll raise a terrifying clone army
占领全世界
to take over the whole world
之后呢  谁知道呢
After that, who knows?
我多半还要单纯找个乐子
Maybe, just for the heck of it
火烧全世界
I'll burn it all down
最后那句你别传出去
That last part is just between us
那要什么时候开始找这个乐子
When's all this fun gonna start?
我按下那颗红色按钮就能开始了
As soon as I push that red button
那颗按钮吗
That button?
看着挺复杂
Looks complicated
没什么
Nah
单纯就一颗小按钮罢了
It's just a simple little button
随便哪个白痴都可以按
Any idiot can push it
随便哪个白痴吗
Any idiot?
随便哪个白痴
Any idiot
这颗按钮
This button?
随便哪个白痴吗
Any idiot?
对  就那回事
Yeah, that's what I said
随便哪个白痴都可以按
Any idiot can do it
有一件事你没有考虑到
There's one thing you hadn't planned on
什么事
What's that?
我就是随便哪个白痴
I'm any idiot
秘方已取得
Formula acquired
大爷堡万岁
All hail the Grand Patty
海之霸
大爷堡
蟹堡王
蛋黄酱
大爷堡
裤头村
大爷复制缸
本大王接下来的毁灭行动
For my next royal act of destruction
是要把全天下烧个精光
I will set all of creation on fire
再烧一遍
again
马屁精
Suck-ups
按理来说那是我的点子
By all rights, that idea was mine
被拍马屁的应该是我才对
They should be sucking up to me
你对于计划挺有品味的  小不点
You had good taste in plans, tiny
现在来吃吃看你是不是真有味
Now let's see if you have actual good taste
疼死了
Pain
你觉得怎么样啊  老螃蟹
How'd you like that, Krabsy?
我从前亲自打爆他才比较爽
I liked it better when I used to smush him
派大爷
GrandPat
时旅柜完完全全发癫错乱了
The Time Closet went all wack-a-doodle ding-dong
你不该来这里的  派大爷
You shouldn't be here, GrandPat
所以我们要带你回到正确的时间线
So we've come to return you to your proper timeline
入侵者
Intruders
来人啊
Guards
押走他们
Take them away
我们就不能最后吃一餐吗
Don't we get one last meal?
那办法对我们行不通
Well, that didn't work out for us.
不知道对世界行不行得通
I wonder how the rest of the world did.
还是别那样了
Let's not do that.
好
Yeah.
那这次先砸晕他
This time let's clobber him first!
不用
No!
我有个更好的办法
I have a better solution.
只要倒退一点点
I'll just rewind a bit and...
大家进时旅柜
Everybody, into the Time Closet!
便宜货超市
我准备好过
I was ready
一把水动力锅铲
A hydro-dynamic spatula
带左右铲的配件
with port and starboard attachments
还有涡轮发动机
and turbo drive
抱歉  零钱不用找了
Sorry, keep the change
我准备好过
I was ready
给
Here
带着这把锅铲
Take this spatula
飞去蟹堡王
fly to the Krusty Krab
拯救世界吧
and save the day
什么
What?
相信我
Trust me
你能行的
You got this
我们能行的
We got this
你是谁  美丽的陌生人
Who are you, beautiful stranger?
你有点眼熟
You look kinda familiar
我只是一个小海绵
I'm just a simple sponge
有着一份工作
with a job
现在你也有工作了
Now you have one
现在  谁准备好了
Now, who's ready?
我准备好了
I'm ready
谁准备好了
Who's ready?
我准备好了
I'm ready
谁准备好了
Who's ready?
我准备好了
I'm ready
来吧  派大爷
Come on, GrandPat
一起回到现代吧
Let's go back to the present
不要
No
我本来还要炒股
I was gonna play the stock market
投资高菲高伯才对
and invest in Goofy Goober's
我知道是谁赢了泡泡碗
I know who wins the Bubble Bowl
走了  达奇
Come on, Dutch
看看我多厉害
Just look at me go
派大星
Patrick
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
快来
Come on
走了  兄弟
Let's go, buddy
刚刚那是怎么一回事
What the heck was that all about?
有个蟹黄堡
A Krabby Patty
落地不超过五秒就还能吃
Five-second rule
那么
So...
你们说派大爷末日成功阻止了吗
do you think we averted the GrandPat apocalypse?
小鬼头给刚刚的事件取了这个名吗
Is that what the kids are calling it?
只有一个办法能找到答案
Only one way to find out.
我看着挺正常的
Looks pretty normal to me!
等下  快看
Wait, look!
老奶奶村
Grannyville?!
忘了带回章鱼老奶奶了
We forgot about Granny Tentacles!
她在那
There she is!
老奶奶女皇驾到  闲杂人等退散
Make way for Empress Granny!
这张一定得贴进我剪贴簿里
This one's for sure going in my scrapbook!